(Let it go.)
=Revenge From A Wife=
=Episode 2=
Grass gives it form.
Simplicity conceals mastery.
(Xiao Che, the Emperor)
Roujia would've loved it.
My sister always loved
simple things like this.
I'm sure her spirit is moved
by Your Majesty's devotion.
Which artisan made this?
I want to reward him in person.
Your Majesty,
fate was unkind to him.
After finishing this screen,
he had an accident
and passed away.
An accident?
Rushing it for the memorial
must've taken its toll.
He was too frail to endure it.
I've already had his body
sent back to his hometown.
His family will be compensated.
What a pity.
Such craftsmanship is rare.
Roujia had a kind heart.
She couldn't bear to see people suffer.
Ask the Imperial Household Department
to grant his family more aid
as a testament to
Roujia's compassion.
Your Majesty,
he's only a grass weaver.
Yes.
I understand.
Don't be afraid, Shouhe.
I'm here.
I'll see you off.
(My wife,)
(Wanniang,)
(I must)
(go on ahead.)
(Don't seek revenge.)
(Let this matter rest.)
Let go.
(Shouhe,)
(let me stay with you a little longer.)
Wanniang.
What's wrong?
Where's my benefactor?
Shouhe...
He's dead.
Mother.
You were His Majesty's wet nurse.
You must know what to do.
My husband only went to the palace
(Qing'er, Nanny Liu's Daughter)
to earn enough
for a fur collar for me.
But when he came home,
only half his body remained.
(Nanny Liu, the Emperor's Wet Nurse)
His clothes
were stuffed with dry grass.
Consort Chen took my husband from me
and made me lose our child too.
Nanny Liu,
can you really let go
of what happened back then?
I lie here day after day.
How could I let it go?
Back then,
I only lit one incense stick in secret
for the late Empress.
Consort Chen had my leg sawed off
and drove me out of the palace.
I wish I could tear her apart.
But in this condition,
I can't even make it out the door.
Then let me go back in your place.
I'll make Consort Chen
pay in blood for what she did.
I can get you into the palace.
But...
First, you have to die once.
I've already died once.
♪Sunset fades beyond the lonely city♪
♪Dusk snow paints the green hills♪
♪A lone rider storms the old pass♪
♪Drunk, I gaze by lamplight♪
♪Old friends have all drifted away♪
♪My broken sword rusts, as do I♪
♪Jackdaws cry into the night♪
♪Half a banner snaps in the wind♪
♪In dreams, I return to the camps♪
♪Moonlight chills my armor♪
♪Life is a dream through many winters♪
♪I gaze beyond the edge of the world♪
♪Parting sorrow spills across the moon♪
♪The moon and wind mean nothing now♪
♪History turns to ash before ink dries♪
♪Who plays the zither
and sighs at the pavilion?♪
♪The past has faded away♪